音高与声音。我们从歌唱过渡到说话。有趣的是，各种语言
Pitch, sound. Let's transition from song to speech. Interestingly, languages are
使用的音高并不相同，所以必须认识到你原本的音高
spoken at different pitches, so it's important to recognize the pitch you're
以及你要转向的音高。虽然英语使用者有数百万，
coming from as well as the pitch you're heading toward. Even though there are
男女都有，但英语大致会落在一个总体音高范围内。
millions of English speakers, both male and female, there's a general pitch range
请听这段音频，它从一位音高很高的日本女性
into which English falls. Listen to this audio clip, ranging from a Japanese woman
一直到一位音域低得多的阿拉伯男性。
speaking at a very high pitch to an Arabic man speaking in a much deeper register.
You'll notice that English is in the middle. In Spanish, this is the sound of
the Spanish. This is the Swedish sound. This is the German language. This is the
Norwegian language. This is the French sound. This is the American sound. This is
the Danish language. This is the Russian sound. This is the Turkish language. This
语言。这是阿拉伯语。一般来说，对美国人而言，较高的
is the Arabic language. Generally speaking, to Americans, a higher pitch
音高会传达紧绷或焦虑的状态，听者会相应作出反应，即使
indicates stress or tension, and they will respond accordingly, even if you're not
你其实并不紧张。当然，用第二语言说话可能会让人紧张；
stressed. Of course, speaking in a second language can be stressful, to match your
要让你的英语说话声音匹配你母语中最低沉的声音。
speaking voice in English to your deepest voice in your own language.